record.
>> The real men are care about the topics.
Margaritas,
>> what do we call front runners? Huh? The
guys that don't front runners.
>> The people that aren't here. The people
that aren't here, front runners.
>> Oh, Dan showed up today. Yeah.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Yeah. The guys and girls that want the
rest of the story are here.
>> Yeah.
>> All right, Calvin.
>> Calvin Watkins, Dallas Morning News. Uh,
Jerry, uh, will you can you guys just
assess what you've done this weekend
with the draft class and things and
obviously the trade as well with
winners?
>> Well, I'm ready for you a little bit
here. So, I'll start with really on with
my notes, but uh
>> we have uh five first round draft picks
that we didn't have this time last year
on defense.
Quinnon, Clark, I'm taking liberty.
Gary, DS, and Lawrence.
So, right there, we've added first five
first round picks that weren't a part of
the team this time last year.
We've added nine new players on defense
this off seasonason between trades and
free agencies.
Nine new on defense. We've added nine
new defensive coaches out of 10 coaches
on defense. We've added nine new ones.
We not only that and coach could speak
to that if you want any but we have
changed the concept of what we're doing
defensively.
The facts are that we have executed on.
We got to see exactly how it's going to
how it's going to be, but we've executed
on a dramatic change. The other thing,
and I can say it this way, and it's not
in any way to be, uh, talking from any
vantage point, but, uh, Brian is a head
coach that has spent a lot of time in a
lot of rooms in the NFL to, uh, be at
his age. You've heard me say that, but
he has absolutely after that year we had
last year on defense, he has absolutely
had to just tunnel vision, burn a hole
in from the standpoint of interviewing
all the coaches that we hire, from the
standpoint of looking at the schemes and
seeing their ideas about the schemes. He
has gone through a doctor's degree from
Harvard in terms of at least putting
this in place so that we can now go
coach them up and execute it. So we have
sat here and added the personnel
dramatic change of I think someone said
that uh Rashadi you said there were nine
new players 12 on defense. Yeah, it's
like 12 or 13 new faces
>> on defense, three on offense as we sit
here tonight to give you an So, it's
been a dramatic change in the bones of
whatever it takes to step out here and
play some defense. Now, we'll see where
we go from here.
>> I know Joe, you said you had to look in
the mirror, Shotty, did you have to do
that as well? Look in the mirror to say
we got to make some changes here.
>> Yeah, absolutely. I mean, you know, you
look back on last year and uh we didn't
win enough games. You know, you got to
win games. You got to get in the
playoffs, get in the postseason, and and
you got to play your best football. And
so, uh, we knew that changes had to be
made, but when you make changes, Calvin,
you better make sure you're making the
right changes. And when you make the
right change, it starts with getting the
right people. Start with getting
Christian, the staff, and then getting
to work with these guys, you know, and
the scouts and doing free agency first.
And you don't get them all right. And if
you don't get one, you don't get upset.
You just pivot and find the next one.
And that's what these guys are so good
at. Uh but what I'm most excited about
is the chance to get out on the grass.
Uh starting with the, you know, the
rookie mini camp next week. The
offseason program starts on Monday. Uh
but getting these guys that were so
excited, these new faces here and get
them up to speed and now it's our job to
as coaches take the development to the
next level.
>> Clarence Hill DLLS Cowboys. I know each
season is its own, but you do have the
quoteunquote 30-year drought and that's
the goal is to take the next step. How
ready are you after what you've done
this off seasonason with the draft or
presency to take the next step and end
that quote unquote 30-year draft?
>> Did you say 30-year draft or 30-year
dout?
>> Since you since you've been to the Super
Bowl.
>> Well, I understand the context you put
the 30-year drought in. Okay. Uh uh I
haven't been living like it was a
30-year draw drought and I I don't it's
been each year the opportunity. Someone
asked me and and uh I understand where
you're talking about uh you'd like to
have done better. But we've done some
good things around here that when I go
to sleep at night I can hang my hat on
that were good things over this last 30
years. Now, we didn't we you're talking
about the Super Bowl, of course, and you
you may even take it on down to the to
the u uh uh to the championship game and
really if you want to get pinpointed,
get it lower than that. Uh um the you
have to
uh be able to live in other disciplines.
Uh it isn't failure to be the second or
third or fourth.
it is in the NFL. And so you got to
learn to live with that. And this this
shuffle you're we're just talking about
right here. The very act of it, what
we're doing, the dramatic thing, the
trades we made last year, it's pretty
pretty it's pretty dramatic stuff in in
my eyes. You'd like for it just to run
smoother. But we hadn't stopped them
four years before last year either.
>> And so uh look at it. It's the only way
you can go if uh you're not going to
step down and I'm not going to do that.
And so you got to change it. Got to
change that mirror.
>> I guess forget
>> from a personal it's a personal
standpoint. We speak like this is all
the show. It isn't. It isn't obvious. I
wish everybody everywhere could see the
uh the way we make a decision there and
uh they'd quit worrying so much about me
sitting there.
>> And and I guess we get to 30 years.
We've talked several times throughout
the offseason. You pointed out how
Seattle's went from out of the playoffs
to the Super Bowl. New England out of
the playoffs to the Super Bowl. You
already feel you have a championship
level offense. Have you done enough
in the offseason to take that next step
is what I'm asking you regarding that
last
>> Let me give you an easy one. We've done
enough to improve before where we ended
up last year.
>> And now that's a trick because we need a
lot more than just improve on what we
did last year. we can materially improve
to where if we should be able to be as
effective on offense generally in my
mind we've done enough to start talking
about getting up there where we try to
be and which uh and I think if we play
the defense that we dream of playing
with the changes we've made and we can
continue improving or doing what we did
offensively last year uh that we've got
a heck of a future around here.
Will Todd Archer with ESPN. If you go to
look at your draft class, is there a
commonality in either traits or
temperament that that you see among
these guys?
>> Yeah, I mean, I think what we have is I
think we have athletes and guys that
love football and play football the way
that the staff wants to play. Uh we saw
that in their college play and we're
hoping they bring it along when they
come in here. It's a new opportunity for
them and and coach is going to set the
stage that way, but we feel like they
got the football character to do the
things that we need them to do. And
Jerry, you talked about the defensive
staff. I think the average age is maybe
five or six younger years younger than
it was even last year. What kind of
energy do you see from those guys to
take the guys you've added here, the the
five first round picks, the guys you
added in?
>> They don't know that they can't do it.
They don't know that they can't do it.
And they are uh they're there in the
eyes of their their boss. Uh and that's
what we're doing. And uh you can add
that to that list of things that I was
just talking to you about about how this
is different than it's been over the
last uh uh 10 years or so. And again, I
don't want to it's not fair. It's just
not the case that people who coach these
teams who people played on these teams
that we've had over the last several
years that they be the involved where
we're trying to improve. There's no
other way to say it. We've got to get
better than we have been if we're going
to come out at the end of the year
better off. So, u yeah, I think without
a doubt that uh you just about I don't
even know if I could list the ways you
could change it up anymore than we've
changed it on the field and as far up as
the coaching staff, I don't know that
you could.
John Mich athletic uh for Brian uh Drew
Shelton, how what did you like about him
and how does he fit into your offensive
tackle uh competition?
>> Yeah, we we really like his smooth his
smooth footwork. He's in a good athlete,
plays well in space. Uh we think he
again is a guy that's going to go out
there and he's got a really good
understanding of angles and how to get
in people's way. Uh we just like the
traits, you know, and we bet on a guy
that's played, I think, 34 starts. uh
and uh we think that get him in here to
compete with some of the guys we got and
uh we're looking forward to throwing him
in the mix with Gayton and Nate Thomas
and those guys and he'll be a left
tackle that's got some guard
versatility, but we also expect him to
be able to swing to the other side as
well.
>> And then for Jerry, when you look at
your total class that you were able to
bring in, how does it compare to what
you thought you could potentially get,
you know, a couple days before the draft
started? Is it exceeded your
expectations or did it meet your
expectations? where where would it kind
of compare for you?
>> Uh that first pick uh was uh uh we got
we got lucky on that one to be able to
do that. Uh and I think the biggest he's
a fa fabulous football player. But, uh,
when you think about one of the most
glaring things in my mind, in our minds
that we didn't do on defense was
communicate,
was communicate, right? When it's time
to get people set up to be in their best
position to make a play. That's what
this guy was
built to do and coached and grown up to
do. You'd heard his background
yesterday, coaching everywhere in it,
generations of it. and then uh he's put
it out there. So uh you need you a cere
cerebral cerebral guy and we got him. U
I don't know that I could have have
really said and planned and said we got
to get that done right there. If id had
that kind of attitude about getting it
done would have probably given away the
draft to try to get there. So we had to
have it come to us some degree. Nick
Harris fourst star telegram with Deon
Moore anybody for the panel uh just what
did you see from him in the evaluation
process does he have positional
versatility and then speak to your
comfort on the injury history as well
>> the long athletic corn corner that can
play press he can play off he can play
zone schemes and when you do pattern
match and some different things on
defense he can do those he understands
spacing and stuff like that he has the
ability to tackle he's a big guy who can
bend and run and change directions
mirror double move routes things like
that um the the the health thing you Our
doctors and trainers gave him a medical
grade that we thought was passing. Uh,
and he did not miss a game last year.
So, we feel good about where he is and
excited about adding him to the team. A
big athlete that can think, feel good
about it.
>> And obviously, you guys finished off a
linebacker trade yesterday. You guys
done in that market and definitely could
add depth in that in that room or are
you looking more at the free agent
market?
>> No, I don't think you're ever finished
uh building a room. I mean, you you're
always looking for ways to improve it.
uh and all the way up to the end of the
draft, we were looking at guys who might
could help us. Some cases we went in
different directions because we thought
it was the better choice to make, but
you know, I think our eyes are wide open
as we move forward to, you know, always
looking to improve.
>> Tommy, Dallas Cowboys.com for the panel,
what enticed you about LT Overton and
where do you see him fitting in on the
defensive line? Chris talked about the
fourey position at defensive tackle. Is
that a role that you can envision him
fulfilling?
>> S you going.
>> Yeah, go ahead.
>> Um just u he played at Alabama, he
played all over the line of scrimmage
and in this defense you have to line in
multiple linements. You can line up help
inside outside that the deal is being
able to play knockback and then being
able to play gap and a half and also the
athleticism to move around on the
defensive front. So versatility does
matter this defense and then playing at
the high level that he did at Alabama.
who feel like he can come in here and
contribute at the at a level right now
that can help the defense.
>> Again, for the group,
>> best it was best described
by one of our guys. U we would love to
have OSA,
but we couldn't afford OSA.
So, we got a guy that does a lot of the
things he does little bit differently.
does a lot of things he does for one we
could afford
and that gave us what we had wished we
could have kept by keeping him and
others can't have that kind of uh price
payer uh player and have the other
complimentary players we've got to go
with him. So I think that best says it
all. I too had to work through that and
I said man this is we're talking like we
were when we had OSA. Uh, and I felt
good about that, by the way. But, uh,
this gives, uh, the kind of combination
of things that they wanted to really be
able to, uh, uh, give them their options
on how they play that interior of the
line.
>> And with the draft selections now over,
how important is the UDFA period for
you? What are your goals to make
additions there?
>> It's a big big part of what we do. I
mean, now, you know, Stevens always
talks about the 365 and this is the
extension of it. There's players that
weren't drafted that we like. We're
going to go through that and see what we
can add. Um, as soon as the draft is
over with, now we start that whole
process. But, um, it doesn't matter
where you come from. You know, that we
we talk about that all the time, you get
the opportunity. So, there's been free
agents and guys that we found that have
played big roles for us.
>> You know, we've always this has been a
big deal for us from the beginning.
We've always felt like you're picking
up, you know, eighth and ninth round
picks. If you'll recall, the draft used
to be 12 rounds. And uh we've always
spent a lot of resources getting
organized. Our guys are back there
getting organized right now. So, when
the draft's over, we can get after it.
And I I do think there's, you know,
we're going to need about, you know, 10
to 12 players uh to finish out our 90.
and uh uh feel really good that we're
good and organized and uh you know have
some players that if they fall through
uh that were really fired up about
getting that we were having to debate
you know with that seventh round pick uh
you know there were three or four guys
we were really debating who should be
the last pick and you never know
sometimes those guys fall all the way
through.
Yeah,
>> Joe White, Dallas Morning News. Um, a
behind the scenes video, Brian showed
that you were talking about Jan Barum as
one of the guys that was on your list
that would have been heartbroken if you
didn't get them. Um, how did that
exercise, I guess, help this draft
process with you? What did it make you
feel? And how much did it help to get a
couple guys on that list that you didn't
have to be heartbroken about?
>> Well, no, we were sitting in draft
meetings and, uh, Jerry actually was
telling me kind of how he has done his
process really the most part, big part
of his life. And you know, like he
talked about a little bit last night,
you know, if you wake up tomorrow
morning, you look at that draft board
and who will you be disappointed, you
know, uh, if they're not on your roster.
And so, uh, right after we broke that
day session, I went back and was looking
at the draft board and made my list of
guys. And, um, you know, fortunately for
us, we were able to get a couple of
those guys, uh, guys that'll have a huge
impact for us for us this year. And, uh,
Jan was certainly one of those guys. and
why the flexibility off the ball, on the
ball, power, violence that he plays
with. Um, and uh, it was a really cool
way of doing this process that I've
never done. Um, and uh, it kind of it it
helped some good conversations uh, get
worked out.
>> And then Jerry Will has talked about um,
Christian Parker's vision and how he
explained that to the scouts seeing all
that. From your perspective, what was it
like to see Christian Parker as a first-
time DC give his vision, explain to you
guys, and help build your board the way
now that the draft is over?
>> I made my mind up that I was going to
know more
through this draft process
than I knew when I was looking at our
defense over the last couple of years.
what we're trying to accomplish and how
we were trying to coordinate it. And I
made my mind up that through the
interview process as well as the process
of talking about the players to play in
this play that I was going to I was
going to get out of this draft process
and where we are with this personnel
right now and I was going to know more
not necessarily feel better, but I was
going to know more about what we're
trying to do out there this year. Okay.
And um uh he uh was one of the better
teachers for me and articulate guys of
uh turning the light on for me of some
of the things he wanted to do. So the
first thing you got to do is peel that.
Well, we do it this way around here. You
got to peel that out and sit there and
work real hard to see where he's trying
to go. He's very impressive like that.
And if he can do it to this one, then
he'll be a whiz doing it to those
players and their minds and their
execution out there. Seriously, it uh uh
really uh gave me. Now, don't ask me to
get on the board and recall,
I can't do that for you. But if somebody
uh will put it up there and then uh tell
me again, I recognize it better than I
did when we started. And he was a big
part of that. And what was really cool
for me, honestly, I've been around a
long time, to see these two gentlemen
over here, there's not many owners that
want to know what gap and a half means
and and stack and fall back and things
like that. It was really cool how they
jumped in and were curious and would ask
questions and um I think it's it's
awesome. Testament to them.
>> Well, I'm the general manager.
>> Yeah, you're both
>> Jarell, CBS Sports. Jerry, you talked
about having a greater understanding of
the defense than you did in years past.
How do you feel like that helps you
moving forward in your player
acquisition 365 days a year?
>> When I look back and I see uh where
we've had some of our disappointments is
when we've uh uh played well, had good
relatively speaking, have been in the
ballpark with our record. But when we
got down to that playoff kind of
football, it's pretty obvious. We can
all add and we can all see. And that's
that's a that's that's obvious right
there. And so it was through the eye
that right there that uh it almost I
said this last night and I I don't know
that I approached things like this, but
it's almost as though I was going to
change it no matter what.
No matter what, we're gonna change
things around here and we're gonna see
and try see if something else works. So,
that's not the way to do things, by the
way. Just change it because you want to
change it. You should evaluate uh its
contribution to what you're changing
into those kinds of things. But it was
very healthy. It was very healthy. But
what it did do, no matter what you say,
if you look at these results where we
are here tonight, and that's why I
started off with that, between the
coaching, the scheme, the players, and
everything else, we did change it for
change's sake. Now, it was more than
that hopefully.
>> Tim,
>> Tim Kalashaw, Dallas Morning News, part
of the Hurst Empire. This is for Jerry
and uh Stephen
because you've been doing this a long
time. We've had some scandals.
>> I think we started the SpanishAmerican
War back in the day, but that was
something else.
>> Um,
when you get an opportunity to make a
trade in the first round and get those
two fours back, you don't have time to
sit there and have a phil philosophical
discussion about trading with the
Eagles, but you must think about that or
have thoughts about that. you're helping
Howie do his job by doing your job. How
does that whether you discuss that a
week beforehand or a month or ever? How
does that play into trading specifically
with the Eagles, the team that's been
successful? Well, this gives me a chance
to do something that I uh want to do,
and that's say the guys that that at Guy
that is doing an outstanding job of
working through and working with the the
relationships on the end is this one
sitting right next to me. And uh I uh
was really uh complimentary
uh about how we ended up uh with uh that
and uh got a lot of good methods out
here. It's not just picking a phone up.
There's a lot more information that you
know about where they are going to go or
how far they will go. So there's a lot
of other stuff going on. You need to
know your universe real good. And so if
you eliminate
all the teams that I want to beat their
ass, you wouldn't have anybody to trade
with, so to speak. And so, yeah,
Philadelphia has a certain edge to it.
Uh, but you could always rationalize and
say, well, uh, I'd like to, uh, have
some success with that trade, and at the
end of the day, I got a bigger grin out
of it than they did. You know, I would,
you know, the thing I would say is, you
know, it's not goes both ways. I mean,
he's helping us do our job, too.
>> We really felt great that we'd get that
guy and pick up two fours, and we think
we may have gotten two great football,
three great football players with those
fours. So, you know, it's just having
confidence in what you're doing. I mean,
we traded with the 49ers twice already
this off season, and they're ever bit
the rival in some some point, some
degree as the Eagles are. And I get
asked the same thing about that. But,
you know, we're doing what's in our best
interest. And we feel like if we do our
job ultimately and get the job done
correctly, then we're going to go be
able to beat them when it really counts,
not who won the trade, who won that
trade. It's going to be who wins the
game when you're going up against them.
And that's ultimately what we got to do.
Now, you say look at the score the last
couple of times and you can say, "Well,
hey, they got the upper hand right now."
But um understand that. But we're
building toward getting the upper hand.
>> One one of the things one of the things
really that has helped me is uh very
early on even away from football. I mean
I had a lot of players uh that I played
with in college that just weren't
necessarily your best friend. And sure,
when you get into commerce or you get
into trading and buying and what have
you, you really can't let that enter
into it. If you start getting into all
of that, you will get put get you put on
you. So, uh I don't really pay much
attention to uh uh the who I'm talking
to now. Al Al Davis probably the first
thing he tried to really put in my head
is man don't mess don't don't don't even
answer a call from your division said
you can't Jerry this is all about this
is all about strategizing against your
division opponents because you play them
twice and uh you can't get that edge
there it's a very strategic edge
and uh so I wouldn't quite didn't take
that lesson from Al as
Brian and for Will. I was just wondering
on Caleb Dance, whenever you get a
player, a big- time player. You talk
about the kind of leader you think he's
going to be, but everything you see or
read about him is he's in this special
category, and I'm just wondering what
you see in him that people look at him
that way.
>> Yeah, I I think, you know, it's hard to
describe, you know, uh Tim in a lot of
ways. You know, I used the example last
night when we brought these guys in,
some of these guys in for top 30 visits.
People are drawn to him. Uh he's
uh very approachable, very serious.
There's a military background in his
family. There's a coaching background in
his family. He's very curious um about
all kinds of things. And I just think
what I love about him is he is so
comfortable in his own skin that you see
him whether it's walking into the head
coach's office the very first time and
you do putt putt and he's comfortable
and quite honestly kick my ass. Um but
like he he was just very kind. He's like
you want to do it again? I was like no
we'll get we'll get to that later. But
like he's just very comfortable and you
see that in his play. You see that in
the way he takes charge. I think Jerry
was talking about that earlier. The the
communication of this guy is different.
Like he's not asking approval. He's
saying, "Hey, close left." You know, rip
rip Lulu, whatever the calls are, he is
driving the defense. And uh for a young
guy to be able to do that at Alabama,
playing for Nick Sabin, and then going
to a completely different defense in
Ohio State under Jim Nolles and then
Matt Patricia comes in, he's never
wavered. And and that jumped off the
film, that command, and it comes from
self-awareness and confidence.
>> And for me, players Oh, go ahead. Yeah,
I saw him talk to talk about his sister
with her sitting over there yesterday
and you know it wasn't one ounce of
makeup there. It wasn't anything. Boy,
he was just talking. Reminds me of Dak.
He does. And he's a pi piper.
>> And players know players, you know, we
evaluate and everything, but guys on the
field know the other guys on the field.
and that innate respect that everybody
you talk to about him that's played
against him has for him too that kind of
gives you that confidence that what
you're seeing is real as well.
>> Go back real quickly to the Philadelphia
asked you about any comment on
Pittsburgh being mad at you.
>> Um not at all. U uh Mike I won't tell
you all about Mike.
>> Okay.
>> Mike he was getting ready to leave. He
was getting rid of McCarthy. You
mentioned Pittsburgh. Mike McCarth
McCarthy. And I don't want to be
insensitive because they're all
especially with Mike McCarthy up there
now. But uh I really think a lot of
those Rooneyies as well. So I don't want
to get on their bad side, but again, we
all understand what we're doing. But
Mike McCarthy,
uh, we were in our suite
and, uh, the great champion won the
fight out at the stadium and came in and
gave me his belt that he had won.
And so Mike was there and I gave him the
belt.
All right. And so Mike was getting ready
to leave
and he had Delora secretary call and
say, "Did Jerry give me that belt or did
he give it to the coach? What am I to do
with the belt?"
And uh boy, I didn't want to have given
him the belt. I wanted to keep the belt.
And so I said, "Well, I don't know. I
don't know about that." Well, Laura
indicated Jerry needed to just think
about it a second. That's all he needed.
That belt was right there in the office.
Mike McCarthy right there. We got the
people that made that belt
to make an exact copy of that belt. I
took the copy and Mike's got the
original belt and what have you there
with it. But that's Mike McCarthy and
and Stephen. Oh, I went down and I said,
"Stephen, I think you were in the room."
Uh, and did I get or say, "Daddy, you
gave Mike the belt." I said, "God, no.
Did I do that?"
So, uh, we we got that done. But again,
I say that in response long-winded to
the question. Uh, we got I've got some
sensitivity up there with Mike and thank
a lot of those roies and I'm sorry that
we're mad, but boy, I'll tell you what,
we've had it happen to us a bunch of
times. It traded right out from under.
That's why we did those fives.
Uh, City Staples, D210 Sports.
Interesting question for both coach and
Will. Do your kids ever talk to you guys
about some of your draft choices or do
they ever tell you guys what kids at
school are thinking about decisions
made?
>> Yes, my son does. He's 19 now. Um, and I
tell him, "If you want to get college
paid for, don't tell me how to do my
job."
And and my kids uh they question my play
calling more than they question Will and
Jerry and Steven's uh selection of
players. I get hit with the play
calling. Why'd you do that on short
yards? That was stupid. That's what
that's what I get.
>> Nick,
>> uh Brian, are you going to draft to
Florida Gator every year?
>> Only if they get better.
>> Just talk through that moment, too, just
being able to do that back toback years.
>> Yeah. Uh, you know, again, I I'll be
quite honest and the floor people will
get mad at me, but uh, you know, with my
kids going through Auburn and my
daughter being there now. Um,
I still hold on to the na the past, the
96 national championship. Somebody sent
me a picture of me signaling for coach
Spurer. I look really good doing it,
too, by the way. Um, but uh we like good
football players and uh now the way
these guys all move around, I'm sure we
probably drafted a couple other guys
that maybe had a had a stint at Florida
you don't even know,
>> you know. So, uh, but uh, no, it's uh,
it's good fun just to be able to talk
about.
>> Hey, uh, well, when you get to the
seventh round pick, you take Smith and
you know the makeup of your current wide
receiver room. Where do special teams
come in? because he told us like he has
a big special teams background because
to make your roster as the fourth,
fifth, sixth, whatever receiver, yeah,
the guy's gota be
>> it's a big part of it. Doesn't matter
where you get draft and where you come
from, but it's what you add to us and so
that element is there and that gives him
an upper hand. But there's the other
things that he has to do as well, but
that's a part of it that goes in the
evaluation. Quickest way to get on the
field is special teams. He's got an
upper hand because he's done it at a
good level. We'll see if he can do it in
the NFL level.
>> All righty. Thank you guys.
>> Thanks, guys.
Take the back end.